Subhash Mukundan

Associate Director at KPMG India

Summary

For close to 17 years, Subhash has built extensive experience in defining and executing Product Sales & Services strategy to create and mature business opportunities, solution selling and customer value creation. His expertise is in Large account management, Territory management & Large deal management and has good understanding of IT / ITES, Banking, Insurance and Manufacturing Industries.

He has worked in Indian and Asia Pacific markets during his tenure and has performed sales roles leading enterprise accounts as an Account Executive & Sales leadership roles as regional sales manager for defined territories.

Key Strengths:

- Thought Leadership with clarity to define strategy and execute the plan.
- Self-motivated and driven by passion to excel.
- Articulate, with excellent presentation skills.
- Ability to connect and influence at the C-level
- Ability to work in a matrix and culturally diverse organizational structure

Experience

Associate Director at KPMG

September 2014 - Present (2 years 7 months)

Subhash performs role of a Business Development Executive for KPMG's SAP practice and is responsible for Business development & Sales of SAP advisory services for South India. Key responsibility includes – Identification & qualification of opportunities in the territory, manage sales metric, manage SAP Alliance, customer advocacy & thought leadership.

Regional Manager / Branch Manager - IBM Kerala at IBM India Pvt Ltd

January 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 9 months)

As a Territory / Regional manager Subhash lead a business development and sales for IBM Kerala region. He was part of IBM's Geo Expansion program and performed a people manager role managing a sales team.

Key responsibilities -

Drive a strong double digit growth and over achieve on the plan – Focus Industries BFSI, Government. Run an operationally tight territory with adequate pipeline generation; deal clinics, Account workshops with a weekly track.

Deploy the account management model with appropriate allocation of resources in the territory targeting specific clients / Industry.

Drive the strategy to gain wallet share with existing clients by account planning and participation of all brands / business units of IBM.

Develop personal relationship with key influencers / decision makers in the region which matter to the team for closures / solving issues / door openers.

Relationship Manager at IBM India Pvt Ltd

December 2008 - December 2011 (3 years 1 month)

Subhash performed role of an Account Manager and managed large enterprise accounts (Indian and Global accounts) during his tenure. Subhash was successful in growing IBM's wallet share in the accounts assigned to him and bring in YTY growth in revenues.

Key responsibilities -

Build up Account Strategy through Account Planning involving C Level Executives, Execute Business development activities, Engage in building large Services deals.

Part of Integrated Account Global team for ING and Unilever, Interact, Engage, align and execute Global, Local account strategies in the account set.

Integrate Global, Local teams for building up large Infrastructure consolidation, Services deals.

Hold key relationships in the account and be a trusted advisor – create opportunities, influence key stake holders for progression and closure.

Drive deals through structured deal workshops, win plans and attain timely milestones for the account team. Mediate conflicts, issues by driving client and account teams and improve on client satisfaction index.

Account Manager at SAP India Pvt Ltd

June 2008 - November 2008 (6 months)

Subhash was a Large Enterprise Account Executive managing Large Enterprise clients in Bangalore, Chennai & Hyderabad.

Key responsibility -

Steered SAP license sales in specific accounts by leveraging SAP industry solution team, large system integrators and SAP consulting.

Relationship Manager at IBM India Pvt Ltd

January 2007 - June 2008 (1 year 6 months)

Subhash performed role of an Account Manager and managed clients in IT / ITES, Public Sector, Retail and Insurance sectors. He was instrumental in winning Infrastructure & Application services deals from named accounts he was responsible for.

Key responsibilities -

Build up Account Strategy through Account Planning involving C Level Executives, Execute Business development activities, Engage in building large Services deals.

Part of Integrated Account Global team for ING and Unilever, Interact, Engage, align and execute Global, Local account strategies in the account set.

Integrate Global, Local teams for building up large Infrastructure consolidation, Services deals.

Hold key relationships in the account and be a trusted advisor – create opportunities, influence key stake holders for progression and closure.

Drive deals through structured deal workshops, win plans and attain timely milestones for the account team. Mediate conflicts, issues by driving client and account teams and improve on client satisfaction index.

Business Manager at Mastek MSC SDN BHDb

March 2003 - January 2007 (3 years 11 months)

Subhash started his stint in Mastek as an account manager managing two large accounts for Mastek in India - Dell and Fidelity. In a few months Subhash moved to Mastek's Asia Pac Business Unit and was based in Kuala Lumpur. Subhash was responsible for selling Mastek's Insurance Back office system (Elixir) and Stock broking system (PICADOR). He was successful in closing large deals for Mastek in Malaysia and Korean Markets.

Key responsibilities -

Responsible for business development in Malaysian and Korean Markets targeting Financial services Industry (Insurance).

Develop CXO relationships with customers in the region, build strategic partnership with System Integrators for entry into major accounts / new countries for developing large deals / accounts.

Lead solution teams to create / respond to Large RFP's and drive pre-sales engagements for developing opportunities / deal closures.

Sales Engineer at Miyakawa Drives and Controls Ltd

November 2001 - February 2003 (1 year 4 months)

Sales Engineer

- Sales engineer responsible for direct and channel sales in Western India (Maharashtra, Gujarat and Rajasthan) for Toshiba Variable speed drives.
- Identify new markets and ensure effective market penetration in coordination with Toshiba (OEM).
- Identify new business opportunities in manufacturing, Elevators domain and develop solutions by collaborating with Toshiba and drive product demos.

Business Development Executive at Future Focus infotech Pvt Ltd

May 2000 - October 2001 (1 year 6 months)

This was Subhash's first job and was initially responsible for accounts in Bangalore. He was later moved to Mumbai for developing the market and he was successful in bringing new logos for Focus Infotech.

Key responsibilities:

Responsible for selling software solutions to Small and medium business segment in Bangalore.

Interact with customers for requirement gathering & analysis and prepare proposals & presentations by collaborating with the technical team.

Drive resource augmentation business unit, develop existing & new customers to understand their resource requirements and ensure project delivery within assigned time limit.

Skills & Expertise

Requirements Analysis

Pre-sales

Business Planning

Solution Selling

Selling

Outsourcing

Business Development

Management

Sales

Banking

Leadership

Security

Strategic Partnerships

Strategy

SDLC

SAP

Team Management

Business Strategy

Account Management

Business Process

IT Strategy

Vendor Management

Business Analysis

Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Enterprise Software

Consulting

Education

University of Calicut

BE, Electronics&Communication, 1995 - 1999

Kendriya Vidyalaya

School, 1988 - 1994

College of Engg (University of Calicut)

Subhash Mukundan

Associate Director at KPMG India



Contact Subhash on LinkedIn